Paul Carduner - Full Stack Software Engineer

ABOUT

I am a full stack software engineer with 15 years of experience specializing in consumer product development. I like to learn new things quickly and am not afraid of the unknown. I've worked as an individual contributor and in leadership positions across a variety of companies small and large.

My core competencies revolve around web technologies like React, node.js, GraphQL, Google Cloud, and the distributed systems that power modern web products. I have also gone on numerous side quests into native mobile apps, systems programming, compilers, web3, and AI.

I am interested in work where I have the opportunity to challenge myself, learn new things, and solve real problems, in an environment that is fast paced and fun. Bonus points if other people appreciate memes as much as I do.

EXPERIENCE

Dropbox, Seattle Remote - Software Engineer

JUL 2023 - March 2024

• I work on generative AI projects within Dash

Sidebar.com, Seattle Remote — Founding Software Engineer

JAN 2022 - JUL 2023

- Peer-to-peer professional development network for leaders with web/mobile real-time chat, group video calling, and a proprietary group matching algorithm.
- Developed all aspects of the above with a 3-person engineering team.

Career Break

2018 - 2021

- Learned about systems programming and wrote a <u>simple virtual machine</u> <u>emulator in rust</u>.
- Learned about compilers and wrote a C-like programming language called snax that compiles to web assembly. Check out a demo program.
- Worked on other side projects too numerous to list here.

Nori, Seattle - Cofounder and CTO

2017 - 2018

• 6 other co-founders and I started <u>Nori</u>, a blockchain based carbon removal marketplace, where I was responsible for establishing the technology stack and engineering team.

Carduner Consulting, Seattle - Owner

• Did part-time consulting work for a variety of startups/organizations including code.org where I helped upgrade their monkey-patched javascript-in-javascript interpreter without any regressions.

Facebook, Menlo Park & Seattle - Software Engineer / Manager

2010 - 2015

- Site-lead for facebook's Seattle office
 - Responsible for maintaining facebook's notorious engineering culture through a period of <u>explosive growth</u>
- Facilitator for FLiP, a.k.a. Facebook Leadership in Practice facebook's internal engineering management training program
- Engineering manager supporting videos infrastructure and product teams where we worked on:
 - Improving efficiency, performance, and reliability across all aspects of videos including upload, encoding, and playback
 - Launching <u>auto playing videos in newsfeed</u>
- Tech lead and engineering manager on the photos team where I worked on:
 - Photo upload reliability
 - o One of the largest data migrations in facebook history
 - Facebook photo sync
- <u>6 patents</u>

Divvyshot, San Francisco — Founding Software Engineer

2009 - 2010

- YC-backed company where we built one of the first social photo sharing apps with an engineering team of 1.
- Acquired by Facebook

Keas, San Francisco - Founding Software Engineer

2008 - 2009

- Consumer product to help people improve their health using doctor-defined wellness protocols.
- TechCrunch

EDUCATION

Whitman College, Walla Walla - Pure Math

2005 - 2007